I was known as the Blade Dragon,
我被称作“剑龙”
and Eight Provinces Unparalleled.
以及“八州无双”
When there was no man stronger than me,
没有人比我更强
the clan leader, Tatsumi requested that I be an officer.
我们的族长辰巳要求我当军官
He was a pompous man who was proud of his large house,
他是一个傲慢自大的人 以他的大房子为荣
But for the sake of food and for the sake of the dragon, I readily agreed to do it.
但是为了食物、为了龙 我欣然答应了
Wow, what a good drinker you are.
你真能喝酒啊
Good for you!
真厉害
But, Sir Tamiya Gantetsusai…
但是 民谷严铁斋先生
Even though you're called the Blade Dragon,
虽然你被称作剑龙
you cannot slay a real dragon.
但你无法杀死一条真正的龙
So that's why I slashed
这就是为什么
the dragon at the gate,
我砍了门口的龙
and the guts of the cowardly dragon.
取出了胆小的龙的内脏
You're too reckless. I can't understand you.
你太鲁莽了 我无法理解你
I think so too.
我也这么觉得
As a result, I was kicked out of the clan and condemned to death.
结果 我被踢出了氏族 并被判处死刑
I don't regret it though.
但我不后悔
If only I could get the letter of official release, I would be pardoned.
如果我能得到正式释放信 我就会被赦免
Then I could improve my swordsmanship even more.
然后我就能进一步提高我的剑术
I'd cut the house in half this time.
这次我会把房子砍成两半
I cannot understand you after all.
我完全无法理解你
If you ask me, I don't understand you.
你要是问我 我也不理解你
Those swords you're carrying are for dissecting, right?
你携带的那些剑是用于解剖的吧？
What a gloomy fellow you are.
真是个阴郁的家伙
Do you feel good killing sinners, whatever your name is?
那个谁 杀死罪人 你感觉良好吗？
My name is Asaemon.
我的名字是浅右卫门
Yamada Asaemon Fuchi.
山田浅右卫门付知
THE 9TH RANK ASAEMON, YAMADA ASAEMON FUCHI
（试一刀流九位 山田浅右卫门付知）
The Yamada Clan's business is not limited to beheading,
山田家的事业不仅限于斩首
but also includes testing swords and pharmaceuticals.
还包括试剑和制药
We're contributing to society.
我们在为社会做贡献
Even more than you.
甚至比你做得更多
So are autopsies…
尸检也是
the elucidation of the human anatomy
阐明人体解剖学
is a noble mission to advance medicine.
是推动医学进步的崇高使命
I will not forgive you if you insult me.
如果你侮辱我 我是不会原谅你的
Well, I don't mind.
好吧 我不介意
-Just don't get in my way, okay? -Hey wait!
-别妨碍我就行了 好吗？ -喂 等等
Do you have any ideas?
你有什么主意吗？
Of course I do.
我当然有
We're going to destroy our competitors.
我们要消灭竞争对手
It's more efficient to search for the elixir later.
之后 寻找灵药的效率会更高
And most of all, I can wield my sword to the fullest!
最重要的是 我可以把我的剑术发挥到极致
I thought that in this age of peace,
我还以为在这个和平年代
there would be no more thrilling fights.
不会再有惊心动魄的打斗了
He has a point.
他说得有道理
This fight is like curse poison.
这场战斗就像诅咒毒药
The longer the bugs are left inside, the deadlier the last one will be.
虫子被留在里面的时间越长 就越致命
But will it really be that easy?
但这真的那么容易吗？
There are more poisonous insects out there.
外面有更多的毒昆虫
If the Government grows impatient, they'll just bring out the next insect.
如果幕府变得不耐烦 他们就会带来下一只昆虫
One that's stronger, and more poisonous.
更毒、更强的昆虫
Interesting.
有意思
Stand back.
退后
What the hell is this thing? A fish?
那是什么东西？一条鱼？
He's wearing prayer beads, but is he a monster? A creature?
他戴着念珠 但他是怪物吗？生物？
It looks so unrealistic and ridiculous.
它看起来如此不真实又荒谬
There's so much I don't understand, but…
有太多我不理解的东西 但是
my instincts are telling me
我的直觉告诉我
that this island is dangerous.
这个岛很危险
What a pain.
真是麻烦
Gabima--!
画眉丸
-I told you to stay back. -Yes, sir.
-我说了让你退后 -是
It seems… like a creature.
它看起来像某种生物
The Law of the Shinobi, rule number five.
《忍者法则》第五条
Never face an unknown opponent.
永远不要对抗未知的对手
Shall we run?
我们要跑吗？
Together? Or alone?
一起跑？还是一个人跑？
Gabimaru, are you okay?
画眉丸 你没事吧？
This place is dangerous.
这地方很危险
I can't believe you're hurt this badly.
真不敢相信你伤得这么重
That's not what I mean.
我不是这个意思
Let's get out of here.
我们快离开这里吧
What are these things?
那些是什么东西？
They're smiling? Are they real…
他们在笑吗？他们是真的吗？
Stay calm.
保持冷静
Don't get distracted.
不要分心
I'm surrounded.
我被包围了
I've had enough. Don't think about anything else.
我受够了 不要再想其他东西了
Gabimaru!
画眉丸！
Ninja Art, Fire Master!
忍术 火法师
Don't think about anything else.
不要想其他东西
Just kill…
为了生存…
to survive.
杀就对了
I'll get pardoned, and escape from this bloody world.
我会得到赦免 并逃离这个血腥的世界
Just kill.
杀就好了
I knew this was a dangerous mission.
我知道这是个危险的任务
But I was wrong.
但我错了
Everything is different now
现在一切
to how it was just a few hours ago.
都跟几小时前不同了
Everything I'm seeing… is very out of this world.
我所看到的一切 都非常脱离这个世界
Is this paradise or….?
这里是天堂还是…
Don't think about anything else.
不要想其他事
That is not weakness.
这不是弱点
Just eliminate…
只要消灭…
True courage is to follow one's heart.
真正的勇敢是跟从自己的内心
…the enemy in front of me.
面前的敌人
Um, Gabimaru…
那个 画眉丸
Thank…
谢…
Wow! Did you slaughter these all by yourself?
好厉害 这些都是你杀的吗？
No one does it like you, Hollow.
没人能做得像你一样 太棒了
You truly are the man. You're amazing!
你是真男人 太棒了
I'm Yuzuriha.
我的名字是杠
I'm a ninja just like you. That makes us buddies.
跟你一样 我是个忍者 我们该成为朋友
Why are there two beheaders?
为什么会有两个斩首者？
Why did you do that?
你为什么这么做？
When someone helps you, you say, "thank you."
有人帮助你的时候 你应该说“谢谢”
Thank you for helping.
感谢你的帮助
So? What do you want?
然后呢？你想要什么？
We're fighting against each other. There's no reason for you to help us.
我们在互相争斗 你没有理由帮助我们
Don't be so tense.
别那么紧张
Look, the monster is gone.
看 怪物已经死了
Besides, you seem strong and reliable.
此外 你看起来强大又可靠
You're bleeding, but you're still standing.
你流血了 但你依然站着
You were helping that girl just now, weren't you?
你刚才在帮那个女孩 是不是？
Hey…
喂
Want to work with me?
想跟我一起工作吗？
Being in such a dangerous place, I'm so scared.
在这么危险的地方 我好害怕
I'll do whatever you say so please protect me…
你说什么我都会照做 所以 请你保护我吧
Huh? Ow…
什么？
Ouch! That hurts!
好痛！
What the hell?!
搞什么呀？
Your charm will not work on me. I know how the girl ninjas do it.
你的魅力对我不起作用 我知道女忍者是怎么做的
Fine then.
那好吧
You got me. I was just testing you.
被你发现了 我只是在试探你
It's better to regret doing something than not to do it, right?
做过总好过后悔没做 对吧？
But I really meant it when I asked you to work with me.
但我提议一起工作时 我是认真的
Five people is better than three, right?
五个人总比三个好 对吧？
Wait a minute.
等一下
Why are there two Asaemon in the first place?
先来说说 为什么有两个浅右卫门？
This guy here is… um…
这边这位是…
I'm Yamada Asaemon Genji.
我是山田浅右卫门源嗣
I was originally in charge of Moro Makiya, the Apostate.
我最初负责弃信教徒 茂龙牧耶
Makiya was tricked by this woman and died.
牧耶也是被这个女人所骗才死的
This is despicable and out of line with the Warrior Way.
这太卑鄙了 不符合武士之道
I judged that a single beheader was not enough to control her.
我判断一名斩首者不足以控制她
So I have decided to accompany her.
所以我决定也跟着她
He fell for her charm.
他被她迷倒了
I see.
明白了
Genji has always had a soft spot for women. He fell in her trap.
女人一直是源嗣的弱点 他中了她的圈套
I-- I'm originally in charge of her.
那个…我原本是负责她的
My name is Yamada Asaemon Senta.
我叫山田浅右卫门仙汰
Well, here's the thing. Before arriving here,
事情是这样的 在到达这里之前
we encountered strange insects, monsters, and stone statues.
我们遇到了奇怪的昆虫、怪物和石像
We know that this place is pretty dangerous.
我们知道这里十分危险
It's important to find the elixir as soon as possible,
尽快找到灵药很重要
but it's no good if we just rush in and die, right?
不过我们冲进去送死也不太好吧？
You're the one who called me a disappointment.
是你刚才说我很令人失望的
Eh, I don't remember saying that.
嗯？我可不记得说过这个
Well, if the two parties agree to cooperate,
好吧 如果双方同意合作
there should be no problem.
应该就没问题了
Yay! I love you Gabimaru!
我爱你 画眉丸
Ow! What the hell?!
你干什么？
I didn't say I'd work with you. I don't trust female ninjas.
我可没说过要跟你合作 我不信任女忍者
Trust? You think that's important?
信任？你认为那很重要吗？
This isn't kids play.
这可不是儿戏
We can betray each other anytime.
我们随时都可以背叛对方
Even if we find the elixir, only one of us gets pardoned,
就算我们找到了灵药 也只有一个人会被赦免
so let's just use each other until the last minute.
所以 我们就利用对方到最后一刻吧
Or are you scared of me?
还是说 你害怕我？
You're surprisingly naive.
你真是太天真了
Please, Gabi. Help a weak girl.
求你了 画眉 帮帮弱小的女孩吧
I don't have time for that.
我可没那个时间
Oh, yeah.
这样啊
What's in it for me?
对我有什么好处？
You give us your strength and I'll give you intel.
你给我们力量 我会给你情报
For example, you guys seem to be worried about the creatures.
比如说 你们似乎很担心这些生物
But, it's the bugs that are the real problem here.
但是 这些虫子才是真正的问题所在
Butterflies with human faces.
长着人脸的蝴蝶
They're flying around the monster, but their nests and habits are unknown.
它们在怪物周围飞来飞去 但它们的巢穴和习性是未知的
Their scales are supposed to be hallucinogenic and poisonous.
它们的鳞片应该是致幻和有毒的
How do you know that?
你怎么知道？
Moro Makiya.
茂龙牧耶
After we got close, I sweet talked him into it
我们变熟以后 我用甜言蜜语说服了他
and tested it out on him.
并在他身上进行了试验
The centipedes are creepy, but you can leave them alone.
蜈蚣令人毛骨悚然 但你不用管它们
They only eat dead meat.
它们只吃腐肉
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
I tested it on Makiya.
我在牧耶身上试验过了
There were other bugs, but as long as you don't get close, they won't attack.
还有其他的虫子 但只要你不靠近 它们就不会攻击你
I tested it on Makiya.
我在牧耶身上试验过了
What happened to that guy?
那个人 他怎么样了？
I pretended I was dead, caught him off guard, and killed him.
我装死 然后趁他不备杀了他
Many of the objects worn by the monsters
怪物佩戴的许多物品
have a religious design,
都带有宗教图案
and they seem to be derived from Buddhism or Taoism.
似乎是佛教或道教的衍生品
Buddhism and Taoism are inherently different.
佛教和道教 本质上是不同的
It's strange to see them mixed together.
它们混在一起是非常奇怪的
The Buddha statues are strange too.
那些佛像也很奇怪
To me, this island doesn't seem to be a paradise at all.
对我来说 这座岛根本不是什么天堂
I agree.
我同意
It's easy to put it away as a mystery, but the internal structure
很容易把它当作一个谜 但从剑身传来的
and the texture of the muscles transmitted from the sword
内部结构和肌肉质地
are those of a living creature.
却像是某种活物的
You see, there are a ton of things we don't know,
你看 有很多我们不知道的事
so the first step is to cooperate and gather information!
所以第一步应该是合作并收集信息
I'll tell you everything I know.
我会把我知道的都告诉你
Why do you reveal so much information?
你为什么要透露这么多信息？
You want to survive that badly?
这么想活下去吗？
I have only one sister.
我只有一个姐姐
She's ill, but… we had no money for medicine.
她病了 但我们没有钱买药
I became a ninja to earn money.
为了赚钱 我成了忍者
I endured hellish training in the Kasumi Valley of Kai.
我在甲壳霞谷忍受着地狱般的训练
Isn't training at Mizore Valley?
不是在米佐尔谷训练吗？
Yes, that valley.
是的 那个山谷
So then… by the chief of the village…
然后 村长告诉我
I was told, You can't do that… something like that.
“你不能这么做” 之类的话
Then I was kind of betrayed.
然后我差不多被出卖了
Hey, if you're lying, don't talk so long.
喂 如果你在说谎 就不要说那么长了
You noticed? Do I need a reason
被你发现了？我想活下去
for wanting to live?
需要理由吗？
Do I need a special reason?
我需要什么特别的理由吗？
I don't have a reason.
我没有理由
Do I need a reason if I just want to live?
我只是想活下去 需要理由吗？
I don't want to die young and empty.
我不想年纪轻轻就空虚地死去
That's it!
就是这样
Well, maybe samurais can't understand.
好吧 也许武士无法理解
They bet their lives on the Military leader's will,
他们将生命押在将军的意志上
and don't even question it.
甚至都不去质疑
And I want to ask you something else.
我想问你一些别的事
What did you really do to that man, Moro Makiya?
你到底对那个人做了什么？ 那个茂龙牧耶
I didn't really do anything.
我真的什么都没做
Are you curious about the lives of others?
你对别人的生活好奇吗？
If you act like that, you'll die.
如果那样做 你会死的
Fine then.
那好吧
I want information too. It's not cooperation, it's collaboration.
我也想要信息 这不是合作 这是协作
Yes! You're the best Gabi!
没错！你是最棒的 画眉！
Ow! It's hurt!
好疼！
I just got a little excited! What the hell are you doing?
我只是有点太兴奋了 你这是干什么？
I have a wife.
我有妻子了
Well, let's get to the information.
好了 我们来说说信息吧
No, not yet!
不 还不行
We're allies now, so you don't need to give out any more info.
我们现在是盟友了 所以你不需要提供更多信息
Shall I rip out your tongue?
要我撕掉你的舌头吗？
I'm kidding. Just kidding.
我开玩笑的
What have I accomplished since coming to this island?
来到这个岛上以后 我完成了什么？
I've been bewildered by these monsters and this whole situation.
我被这些怪物和整个情况弄糊涂了
What good has my sword done?
我的剑有什么用？
Why am I… so helpless?
为什么我如此无助？
The willingness to change is strength.
愿意改变就是力量
He's taking over after only one month of training?
他只训练了一个月就接手了？
Good job, Toma.
干得漂亮 桐马
Lastly, you will cut the criminal, and you will go up in the ranks.
最后 你要砍了那名罪犯 你的排名就会上升
Which place of punishment is the best?
什么地方的刑罚最好？
I know of a place.
我知道一个地方
Sorry to keep you waiting.
抱歉 让你久等了
I've come to help, Big brother.
我来帮你了 哥哥
You're late!
你来晚了
After a month of infiltrating the Yamada Clan, and rising to this position,
经过对山田家族一个月的渗透 并坐上了这个位置
you're not going to thank me?
你不打算感谢我吗？
I endured torturous interrogation for a month.
我忍受了一个月的严刑拷打
So that's why. You've become even more handsome.
这就是为什么你变得更帅了
How do we escape?
我们要怎么逃走？
It won't be easy to pass the men in the magistrate's office.
要绕过衙门的人可不容易
There's a way to avoid being chased.
有一个办法可以躲避追捕
I'm for it.
我准备好了
Change means changing one's appearance depending on the situation.
变化就是根据情况改变自己的容貌
Brother!
哥哥
It's about understanding the situation quickly and grasping it.
要迅速了解情况并把握形势
Is it a creature? What is that?
那是个怪物吗？那是什么？
Sometimes it's hard to understand the situation.
有时候很难理解情况
I can kill it then!
我能杀了它！
Grasping the situation,
把握形势
that is my brother's strength.
那是我哥哥的强项
He could always grasp a situation.
他总是能把握形势
He did when the feudal lord our father served
当父亲侍奉的领主
committed a crime at Edo Castle
在江户城犯罪
and was ordered to dismantle the clan.
并被命令拆散宗族时
When Mom died of illness due to poverty.
当妈妈因贫困病逝时
The loyal avengers, the 47 ronin ninja,
忠诚的复仇者 47浪人忍者
all 47 of them shall be beheaded!
所有47人全部斩首！
Even when my father participated in the avenging of his lord and was executed.
甚至在我父亲参与 替他的君主报仇而被处死时
Even when I was attacked by bandits.
即使我被强盗袭击了
He would grasp the situation,
他也会把握形势
and take control over it.
并控制它
It's over! Bandit leader, Chobei!
结束了！贼王 吊兵卫！
Come out of there!
快点出来！
Toma, get out of here.
桐马 快走吧
-But, brother! -Come save me later.
-但是 哥哥… -晚点再来救我
I believe in you.
我相信你
The world is not about survival of the fittest.
不是说让最适合的人生存
The fittest survive. Those who adapt are the strongest.
而是适者生存 最能适应的人才是最强的
-Brother… -Toma, let's get these monsters!
-哥哥 -桐马 让我们拿下这些怪物！
Yes!
是！
If he can't grasp the situation, he may run, but always adapts again.
如果他无法把握形势 他可能会跑 但他总是会重新适应
You're a genius at adapting.
你真是适应的天才
The only thing that remains the same is…
唯一保持不变的是…
Brother!
哥哥
The willingness to change is strength.
愿意改变就是力量
We don't need things…
我们不需要
that never change.
一成不变的东西
That's why you're strong, brother.
这就是你强大的原因 哥哥
You monster!
你这怪物！
You'll never get past this point!
你永远也过不了这里！
A monster's weapon is effective against monsters.
怪物的武器能有效对抗其他怪物
Brother!
哥哥
Thanks to you, I was able to take it down.
多亏了你 我才能把它拿下
Brother! Are you okay?
哥哥 你没事吧？
Killing is a sin.
杀人是一种罪过
Insects are living creatures.
昆虫也是生命
Fish are living as well.
鱼也是生命
-These things talk? -You shall not hurt them.
-这些东西会说话？ -你不该伤害它们
Killing is a sin.
杀人是种罪过
Brother. Are these… real gods?
哥哥 这些是真的神吗？
This place is hell, not paradise.
这个地方是地狱 不是天堂
A place where sinners are punished.
一个惩罚罪人的地方
The sins of the lord are the sins of his subjects.
主的罪孽就是他臣民的罪孽
You are condemned to death!
你被判死刑了
Seize the deadly criminal Chobei!
抓住死刑犯 吊兵卫！
Shut up! Sin, sin, sin, you say!
住口 罪罪罪 你说！
Whether it's evil or sin,
无论是邪恶还是罪恶
I don't give a damn! You guys decided that, didn't you?!
我都不在乎！ 那是你们决定的 不是吗？
Follow righteousness? You slaves!
追随正义？你们这些奴隶！
You greedy puppets!
你们这些贪婪的傀儡！
I will not be interfered with any longer!
我不会再受到干扰
I'll do what I want!
我会做我想做的
I'm my own master.
我是自己的主人
I'm my own god!
我是我自己的神！
Your willingness to change is your strength.
愿意改变就是你的力量
Because you change, you stand out.
因为你改变了 所以你脱颖而出
You have an ego that will never break.
你拥有一个永远不会崩溃的自我
Dad… Mom…
爸爸 妈妈
I want to go home.
我想回家
The child of a samurai is now a bandit.
武士家的孩子现在成了土匪
I don't know what's right anymore.
我不知道什么是对的了
I don't know what's right.
我不知道什么是对的
Don't cry, Toma. If you show weakness, you will die!
别哭了 桐马 如果暴露你的弱点 你就会死
If you don't know what's right, then trust only me.
如果你不知道什么是对的 那么就相信我吧
I'm your elder brother! I'm your guide!
我是你大哥 我是你的领路人
I am always right.
我永远是对的
If such monsters are real,
如果怪物们是真的
then the story of the elixir must be true.
那么长生不老药也一定是真的
I've made up my mind. I'm going to kill all of them, monsters and criminals alike.
我决定了 我要杀死他们所有人 无论是怪物还是罪犯
Then the search for the elixir will be unobstructed.
然后寻找长生不老药将畅通无阻
We will drink the elixir we find.
我们会喝下我们找到的灵药
No one can interfere with our way of life,
没有人可以干涉我们的生活方式
not even death!
包括死亡
Will it really go that easily?
真的会那么容易吗？
Huh?
什么？
This is a dangerous island.
这是座危险的岛
Whatever we face,
不管面对什么
we will have survived this predicament.
我们将在这种困境中幸存下来
That's how much of a threat this place is.
这地方就是这么大的威胁
The weak will be eliminated.
弱者都会被淘汰
Subtitle translation by: Mel Nishi
字幕翻译：朱未耒